bloo.com.au 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy

### Overview

The website is owned by bloo (WA) Pty Ltd, trading as bloo.com.au., (aka simply; "bloo"). bloo recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information collected about our customers. For the purposes of this Privacy Statement, the word customers includes visitors to our web sites, subscribers to and users of our services, purchasers of our products and advertising customers. We are bound by the National Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act 1988 in relation to the handling of personal information. Where appropriate we will handle personal information relying on the media exemption (but complying with the Australian Press Council Privacy Standards), related bodies corporate exemption and the employee exemption in the Privacy Act.

### What this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers bloo (WA) Pty Ltd (ABN 24 143 298 668) and its related corporations (as defined by the Corporations Act 2001) (bloo) treatment of personally identifiable information that bloo collects about you when you deal with bloo.

### Information Collection

We collect personal information when we provide our services to you. Generally we will tell you why we are collecting information when we collect it and how we plan to use it or these things will be obvious when we collect the information. We usually collect personal information directly from you although sometimes we may use agents or service providers to do this for us. We may also acquire lists from other sources, both from other companies and from other public documents.

  * bloo collects personally identifiable information whenever you deal with bloo, for example if you register for a bloo advertising account, when you use bloo products or services, and when you enter promotions or sweepstakes.
  * Generally, we ask for your name, email address, birth date, gender, and post code. Once you supply these details to bloo, you are not anonymous to us.
  * Where the internet is used, bloo also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, bloo cookie information, and the page you requested.
  * bloo may also collect your personal information from a variety of sources, including from advertisers, mailing lists, recruitment agencies, contractors and business partners.
  * If, at any time, you provide personal or other information about someone other than yourself, you warrant that you have that person's consent to provide such information for the purpose specified.

### Information Use

bloo uses the information it collects about you for the following purposes.

  * Primarily to provide you with products or services you have requested from bloo.
  * To provide you with news and information about our products or services.
  * To send marketing and promotional material to you that we believe you may be interested in which relates to bloo's businesses or third party businesses.
  * To communicate with you, including by email, mail or telephone, to conduct competitions or promotions on behalf of bloo and third parties.
  * For all purposes necessary and incidental to the provision of any goods or services to you by bloo or anyone on behalf of or in affiliation with bloo.
  * As required or permitted by any law.

We usually collect personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, and in some instances, your financial details. When you are online, we collect information regarding the pages within our network which you visit and what you click on. As a general rule we do not collect sensitive information. However, if we do, it will usually be for the purposes of providing our goods or services and if the law requires us to, we will seek your consent to collect it. We use your information to provide our services to you, to fulfill administrative functions associated with these services, for example billing, to enter into contracts with you or third parties and for marketing and client relationship purposes. Where your personal information is contained within an advertisement which we publish for you, we may also use your information for publication of that same advertisement in other media, in accordance with the terms and conditions of the initial publication. We may share your information with other companies which are related to bloo Pty Limited, within Australia. We or they may also use your personally identifiable information to assist us in improving our products and services and any of us might be in touch to let you know about goods, services, or promotions which may interest you.

If you do not provide personal information as requested by bloo, you understand that bloo may not be able to provide you with one or more services, or the level of service it intends to provide or provides to others.

### Use by third parties

bloo may disclose your information to its service providers and contractors from time to time to help us to provide and market our goods and services to you. We may also share your information with third parties who provide prizes for competitions or reader offers. If we do this we generally require these parties to protect your information in the same way we do.

We may disclose your personal information to other parties, such as our technical service providers, credit agencies, professional advisors and government and regulating agencies as and when required. Furthermore, we may disclose such personal information to you professional advisors and/or representatives when requested in writing by you to do so.

### Use of aggregate data

We may collect certain non-personal information to optimise our goods and services including our Web pages for your computer (e.g., the identity of your Internet browser, the type of operating system you use, your IP address and the domain name of your Internet service provider). We may use such non-personal information for internal purposes, including but not limited to improving the content of our sites. bloo may use personally identifiable information in aggregate form to improve our goods and services including our Web sites and make them more responsive to the needs of our customers. This statistical compilation and analysis of information may also be used by bloo or provided to others as a summary report for marketing, advertising or research purposes.

### Security

bloo strives to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personally identifiable information of our customers. We use a variety of physical and electronic security measures including restricting physical access to our offices and firewalls and secure databases to keep personal information secure from misuse, loss or unauthorised use or disclosure. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure.

### Credit card payments

bloo (WA) Pty Ltd accepts credit card payments from this website. All payments are transacted in Australian Dollars only. bloo (WA) Pty Ltd utilises the services of Ezidebit Pty Ltd to ensure your credit card details are handled safely and securely by a professional payment gateway. Ezidebit is PCI DSS compliant credit card payment gateway. You will be entering your credit card details into a highly secure enviornment protected by THAWTE 128/256bit SSL. Your credit card details are NOT permanently stored on the internet when you pay by credit card from this website. This is very different to when you pay online using a 'real time' payment gateway where your own private and sensitive credit cards details will be permanently stored on a web server somewhere whether you like it or not. We have chosen Ezidebit because bloo (WA) Pty Ltd is not prepared to compromise when it comes to the security and protection of our customer's private and confidential information. Our use of Ezidebit ensures your private and sensitive credit card information will NOT be permanently stored on the internet in any way whatsoever.

### Access to personal information

You have a right to access most personal information we hold about you and if we deny access in some circumstances we will tell you why. To request access, please contact our privacy officer as set out at the end of this document.

### Public information

Any information posted on bulletin boards and/or communicated in chat areas becomes public information. While bloo strives to protect and respect your privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose in a chat room or bulletin board.

### Cookies

Cookies are data that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can facilitate a user's ongoing access to and use of a site. They allow us to track usage patterns and to compile data that can help us improve our content and target advertising. If you do not want information collected through the use of Cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the Cookie feature. But you should note that Cookies may be necessary to provide you with features such as merchandise transactions or registered services.

  * bloo may set and access bloo cookies on your computer.
  * bloo allows other companies that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. The way other companies use their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to bloo's cookies.
  * bloo uses web beacons to access our cookies within and outside our network of web sites and in connection with bloo products and services.

### Editing and Deleting Your Information

bloo gives you the ability to edit or delete your information at any time. Should you wish to do so, please contact us at bloo (WA) Pty Ltd; PO Box 347, South Perth, WA 6951.

### Online links to third parties and co-branded sites

bloo may establish relationships with business partners that allow visitors to our Internet sites to link directly to sites operated by these partners. Some of these sites may be "co-branded" with our logo; however, these sites may not be operated or maintained by or on our behalf. These sites may collect personal information from you that may be shared with us. This Privacy Statement will apply to any personal information we obtain in this manner. bloo is not responsible for the content or practices of Web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our sites. These links are meant for the user's convenience only. Links to third party sites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement or approval by bloo of the content, policies or practices of those third party sites. Once you have left our site via such a link, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party site.

### Other things you should know about privacy on the Internet

Remember to close your browser when you have finished your user session. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You as an individual are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer. Whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet that this information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information in publicly accessible online forums, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

bloo may edit this policy from time to time. We will publish these changes in this policy, as soon as they are made.

### Consent

You consent to bloo using your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy.

### Opting Out or Editing

If you do not want your details to be used for the purposes stated please write to us at bloo (WA) Pty Ltd (Attn: customer service); PO Box 347, South Perth, WA 6951.
